Guide to the Memorial Union Program Council Records 1964-2016
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center
Memorial Union Program Council Records
1964-2016
2006-2015
Oregon State University. Memorial Union.
RG 275
8.00 cubic feet, including 51 photographic prints, 2843 digital photographs, and 1 videotape 9 boxes, including 3 oversize boxes
8.38 Gbytes 3228 files
Special Collections and Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids
The Memorial Union Program Council (MUPC) Records document the administration of this organization and its role in programming campus events. Primarily reflecting activities related to event coordination and publicity, this collection includes artifacts, budgetary documents, contracts, correspondence, digital files, flyers, handbooks, meeting minutes, photographs, posters, publications, reports, and scrapbooks. The MUPC was established in 1948.
Historical Note:
Formed in 1948 as the Memorial Union Activity Council, the Memorial Union Program Council (MUPC) has served as the university's primary body in the coordination of student programming and campus wide events. The organization is managed by a combination of student officers elected at large and volunteers. These members serve on committees that are responsible in planning the combination of ongoing and one time MUPC events that occur on campus every year.
Among the annual events coordinated by the MUPC have included Mom's Weekend, Dad's Weekend, Student Leadership Conferences, the Children's Holiday Party, and the Battle of the Bands.
In 2016, the administration of the MUPC was transferred from the Memorial Union to the Office of Student Leadership and Involvement. While the change did not alter the core function of the organization, the council had to be renamed and is now known as the OSU Program Council. Another change that year was the renaming of the OSU Mom's and Dad's Weekends to the OSU Fall and Spring Family Weekends. As a part of this change, the organization of these two annual events has become a collaborative effort between the OSU Program Council and the Office of New Student Programs and Family Outreach.
Oregon State University. Memorial Union.
Information artifacts.; Born digital.; Digital moving image formats.; Digital photographs.; Photographic prints.; Posters.; Scrapbooks.; Video recordings.
College students--Oregon--Corvallis.; Concerts--Oregon--Corvallis.; Student activities--Oregon--Corvallis.
Colleges and Universities; Multiculturalism; Music; Performing Arts; Women; Artifacts; Corvallis; Electronic Records; Moving Images; Oregon; Photographs; Scrapbooks
The bulk of these materials were transferred to the Special Collections and Archives Research Center in 2017. Records received earlier were originally described as a part of the Memorial Union Records (RG 099).
Collection is open for research.
Other collections in the OSU Special Collections and Archives Research Center that document the work of the Memorial Union Program Council include the Memorial Union Records (RG 099), the Memorial Union Photograph Collection (P 198), and the KBVR TV Moving Images Collection (F/V 170).
Documentation of the major annual events organized by the MUPC, Mom's Weekend, Dad's Weekend, and the Children's Holiday (Christmas) Party, can also be found in the Office of New Student Programs Records (RG 279), News and Communications Photograph Collection (P 057); the Beaver Yearbook Photograph Collection (P 003), Harriet's Photographic Collection (P HC), and the Memorial Union Videotapes (FV 198).
The personal papers of MUPC administrator Leone S. Johnson are also available.
The Memorial Union Program Council Records consist of 10 series. 1. Reports, 1985-2013; 2. Committees, 1989-2015; 3. Staff Meetings, 1964-2013; 4. Handbooks, 1977-2013; 5. Event Planning, 1985-2015; 6. Publications, 1970-2016; 7. Photographs, 2004-2012; 8. Scrapbooks, 1971-2011; 9. Moving Images, 1995-2013; and 10. Artifacts, 2012-2013.
The Memorial Union Program Council (MUPC) Records document the administration of this organization and its role in programming campus events. These records were generated and assembled by the MUPC and include: artifacts, budgetary documents, contracts, correspondence, digital files, handbooks, flyers, meeting minutes, photographs, posters, publications, reports, scrapbooks, and a VHS videotape.
The primary focus of this collection is the coordination of events by the MUPC and the various processes involved in planning them-committee recommendations, budgetary management, staging logistics, publicity, and post event review. Materials illustrating these processes include correspondence, contracts, flyers, meeting minutes, posters, surveys, tickets, artifacts, and evaluation reports. Documentation of some of the events are depicted in photographs, moving images, and scrapbooks.
Administrative activities reflected in these records include program and budget assessment, the publication of event planning guidelines, and policy reviews/updates in staff meetings. These are featured in reports, handbooks, meeting minutes, and publications.
- Reports, 1985-2013; Series 1
  Series 1 consists of reports compiled by MUPC staff that reflect assessment, budgeting, and activities during summer session. This series also contains digital files.
  - Assessment Reporting, 2009-2010 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Assessment Reporting, 2012-2013 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Budget Reporting, 2004-2011 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Summer Term Reports, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Assessment Reporting, 2005-2006
    This folder is made up of 7 born digital files relating to an assessment of the Memorial Union. These files contain focus group questions, learning outcome statements, and a transcript of a group interview of Memorial Union staff. These files are available for viewing in the Reading Room.
- Committees, 1989-2013; Series 2
  Series 2 reflects the work of various Memorial Union Program Council committees and is made up of meeting minutes, notes, correspondence, check in sheets, and committee membership lists.
  - Community Relations and Traditions Committee, 2013-2015 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Entertainment and Recreation Committee, 2012-2015 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - General, 1989-2012 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Holiday Decoration Celebration Committee, 2005 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Marketing Committee, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 1.9)
  - Marketing Committee Notebook, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 1.10)
  - Marketing and Social Media Committee, 2012-2013 (Box-folder 1.11)
  - Marketing and Social Media Committee, 2012 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Marketing and Social Media Committee, 2012-2015 (Box-folder 1.12)
  - Memorial Union Advisory Board, 2013-2014 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - MUPC Inclusivity Committee, 2011-2013 (Box-folder 1.14)
  - MUPC Weekly Committee Check In Sheets, 2012-2013 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Mom's and Dad's Weekend Planning Committee, 2012 (Box-folder 1.16)
  - Mom's Weekend Fashion Show Committee, 2009-2010 (Box-folder 1.17)
  - OSU Spirit, Holidays, and Special Events Committee, 2012-2013 (Box-folder 1.18)
- Staff Meetings, 1964-2013; Series 3
  Series 3 consists of materials reflecting staff meetings and is made up of meeting minutes, agendas, notes, and memoranda.
  - Staff Meetings, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Staff Meetings, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 1.20)
  - Staff Meetings, 2005-2013 (Box-folder 1.21)
- Handbooks, 1977-2013; Series 4
  Series 4 is made up of handbooks, guides, and binders of information assembled as a part of training orientations and reference for MUPC officers. In addition to policy and procedure guidelines, the handbooks also contain blank forms, evaluation reports, maps, and budget information.
  - Event Planning Guides, 2004 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - Memorial Union Election Packets, 1991-2010 (Box-folder 1.23)
  - MUPC Director Binder, 2012 (Box-folder 1.24)
  - MUPC Director's Retreat Packet, 2002 (Box-folder 1.25)
  - MUPC Handbooks for 1977-1978 thru 2004-2005, 1977-2004 (Box-folder 1.26 - 1.30)
    5 folders. Not all years represented, gap from 1989 through 2003.
  - MUPC Marketing Binder, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 1.31)
  - MUPC Marketing Opportunities Guide, 2013 (Box-folder 1.32)
  - MUPC Orientation Handbook, 2012 (Box-folder 1.33)
  - MUPC Orientation Handbook, 2013 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - MUPC Program Advisor Binder, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Student Involvement Event Planning Guide, 2001 (Box-folder 2.3)
- Event Planning Files, 1986-2015; Series 5
  Series 5 documents the planning and publicity of campus events and activities organized by the Memorial Union Program Council. These materials are made up of certificates, contracts, correspondence, event programs, flyers, posters, tickets, information packets, judging forms, meeting minutes, event summary reports, and stage passes. This series also contains digital files.
  - All-University Student Recognition and Awards Banquet, 2002-2010 (Box-folder 2.4)
    Includes correspondence regarding the Jo Anne Trow Woman of Distinction Award.
  - Battle of the Bands, 2004-2008 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Battle of the Bands/Flat Tail Music Festival, 2009 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Battle of the Bands/Flat Tail Music Festival, 2010 (Box-folder 2.7 - 2.10)
    4 folders
  - Battle of the Bands/Flat Tail Music Festival, 2011 (Box-folder 2.11 - 2.13)
    3 folders
  - Battle of the Bands/Flat Tail Music Festival, 2012 (Box-folder 2.14 - 2.17)
  - Battle of the Bands/Flat Tail Music Festival, 2013 (Box-folder 2.18 - 2.20)
  - Battle of the Bands/Dam Jam, 2014 (Box-folder 3.1 - 3.2)
    2 folders.
  - Battle of the Bands, 2015 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Battle of the DJs, 2012 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Battle of the DJs, 2013 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Battle of the DJs, 2014 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Benny Beaver's Birthday Bash, 2012-2013 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Campus Movie Fest, 2009-2010 (Box-folder 3.8)
  - Campus Movie Fest, 2011 (Box-folder 3.9)
  - Children's Holiday Party, 2005-2014 (Box-folder 3.10 - 3.17)
    8 folders.
  - Children's Holiday Party-Planning Notes, 2013 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Civil War Tee Shirt Sales, 2010-2013 (Box-folder 3.18)
  - Connect Week Activities, 2010-2012 (Box-folder 3.19)
  - Dad's Weekend, 1993-2014 (Box-folder 3.20 - 3.31)
  - Dad's Weekend, 2012 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Homecoming Events, 2006-2013 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Leadership Conferences, 2010-2013 (Box-folder 4.2 - 4.4)
  - Lounge Jam, 2009 (Box-folder 4.5)
  - Martin Luther King (MLK III) Lecture, 2006 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - MUPC Diversity Speaker Series, 2010-2011 (Box-folder 4.7)
  - Men's Leadership Conferences, 2006-2009 (Box-folder 4.8)
  - Mom's Weekend, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 4.9)
    Mom's Weekend Fashion Show
  - Mom's Weekend, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 4.10 - 4.14)
    Mom's Weekend Fashion Shows
  - Mom's Weekend, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 4.15 - 4.16)
  - Mom's Weekend, 2008 (Box-folder 4.17 - 4.18)
  - Mom's Weekend, 2009 (Box-folder 4.19 - 4.20)
  - Mom's Weekend, 2010 (Box-folder 4.21 - 4.25)
    5 folders.
  - Mom's Weekend, 2010 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Mom's Weekend, 2011 (Box-folder 5.2 - 5.5)
    4 folders.
  - Mom's Weekend, 2012 (Box-folder 5.6 - 5.11)
    6 folders.
  - Mom's Weekend, 2013 (Box-folder 5.12 - 5.16)
  - Mom's Weekend, 2014 (Box-folder 5.17 - 5.20)
  - Mom's Weekend, 2015 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Mom's Weekend, 1989-2014 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Movie in the Quad, 2012 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Oregon's Birthday Celebrations, 2013-2014 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - OSU Has Talent, 2010-2014 (Box-folder 6.4 - 6.7)
  - Posters for Various Events, 1985-2014 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Renaissance Faire, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - Snow in the Quad, 2006-2011 (Box-folder 6.9- 6.10)
  - Sponsorship For Events, 2002-2010 (Box-folder 6.11)
  - Summer Session Noon Concerts, 2011-2013 (Box-folder 6.12)
  - Taylor Mali and Poetry Slam For Poverty, 2011 (Box-folder 6.13)
  - Tristan Taormino Lecture, 2011 (Box-folder 6.14)
  - Valentine's Day Event, 2013 (Box-folder 6.15)
  - Various Events, 2005-2011 (Box-folder 6.16)
  - Western Wind-Up, 2013-2015 (Box-folder 6.17 - 6.19)
  - Western Wind-Up, 2013 (Box-folder 7.5)
  - Women's Leadership Conference, 1990-2009 (Box-folder 6.20 -6.23)
    4 folders. Nothing for years 1995 through 2000
  - Event Planning Files, 2002-2011
    This folder consists of 378 born digital files reflecting the planning and publicity of various MUPC events. These files include budgetary records, event summary reports, letter templates, posters, registration form blanks, and survey materials. These files are available for viewing in the Reading Room.
- Publications, 1970-2016; Series 6
  Series 6 is comprised of brochures, event calendars, and other media printed for distribution containing information on Memorial Union Program Council members and activities.
  - Event Calendars, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - Informational Brochures, 1970-2016 (Box-folder 6.24)
- Photographs, 2004-2012; Series 7
  Series 7 is made up of photographic and digital images taken by Memorial Union Program Council staff that document various events organized by MUPC. These events include the Mom's Weekend Fashion Show, Battle of the Bands, and the Children's Holiday Party. In total, there are 46 photographic prints and 2843 digital photographs in this series.
  - Children's Holiday Party, 2012 (Box-folder 6.25)
  - Renaissance Faire Vendor Booths, 2004 (Box-folder 6.26)
  - Photographs, 2006-2012
    This folder contains 2843 digital photographs arranged in 22 folders. The images depict Mom's Weekend Fashion Shows and music festivals organized by the MUPC. These files are available for viewing in the Reading Room.
- Scrapbooks, 1971-2011; Series 8
  Series 7 consists of 3 scrapbooks assembled by the Memorial Union Program Council that contain newspaper clippings, photographs and posters documenting events organized by the MUPC and new stories about its members. There are 5 photographic prints in these scrapbooks.
  - Scrapbook, 1971; 7.1 (Box-item 7.1)
  - Scrapbook, 1986; 7.2 (Box-item 7.2)
  - Scrapbook, 2011 (Box-folder 6.27)
- Moving Images, 1995-2013; Series 9
  Series 9 is made up of 1 VHS videotape and 4 digital files containing footage from events organized by the Memorial Union Program Council. Also included is a recording of student auditions for the "OSU Got Talent" competition and an informational video about serving in the MUPC.
  - Mom's Weekend, 1995; 6.1 (Box-item 6.1)
    VHS videotape
  - MUPC-Choose Your Own Adventure!, 2010; 2
    A promotional film to publicize the activities of the MUPC. Video can be accessed here.
  - "OSU Has Talent" Auditions, 2013; 3
    Student auditions for the 2013 "OSU Has Talent" contest. Video can be accessed here.
  - Battle of the Bands, 2013; 4
    Footage from the 2013 Battle of the Bands. Video can be accessed here.
  - Battle of the Bands and Flat Tail Music Festival, 2012; 5
    Footage from the Battle of the Bands and Flat Tail Music Festival. Video can be accessed here.
- Artifacts, 2012-2013; Series 10
  Series 10 is comprised of artifacts created in the course of organizing and managing Memorial Union Program Council events. The items include a backstage pass on a lanyard, a customized portfolio for the Battle of the Bands Director, refrigerator magnets, and animal bag puppets used as craft models at the 2013 Children's Holiday Party.